www.pablocardone.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-garcia-cardone-841077165

Based in Leicester, England, United Kingdom

PERSONAL STATEMENT

First class Business and Management BA and Risk Management MSc graduate currently working as an Applicant Relationship Manager at De Montfort University. Proficient user of MS Office. Strong social, analytical, and written skills gained from academic, work and self-experience.

I am an enthusiastic individual keen to develop a career in Business & Management within an International environment, having experienced different cultures and travelling worldwide along with studying outside my country of origin since the age of 14. Some of my skills include being highly flexible, reliable, outgoing and self-motivated. I also possess excellent time management skills along with a great sense of cultural awareness reflected by my track history of studying and working internationally.

KEY SKILLS

- Collaborating & Teamworking: Developed through teamwork during my IB and University courses along with collaborating with individuals in my hobbies and work.
- Excellent Communication: Enhanced and developed throughout my academic life and work experience.
- **Responsible:** Always delivering each task to the best of my capacity, in time and to a high work and ethical quality standard.
- Leadership: Strong leadership skills developed throughout my academic and work life, such as working as the course representative for Risk Management along with being the only Applicant Relationship Manager for the Americas region within my current job position.
- **Highly adaptable & Flexible:** Able to quickly adapt to new situations and environments, work under pressure and to tight deadlines without any problems.
- Excellence: Always passionate and motivated to ensure that work is delivered to the highest standard and constantly pushing myself to go beyond expectations regardless of any challenges.
- IT Skills: Experienced user of: MS Office (including Microsoft Word, Excel, and Powerpoint), WordPress, Gimp, Google Analytics, PPC/Facebook/Google Ads, copy writing, content writing and SEO.
- **Organized**: Always paying attention to detail and organizing my workload as to further increase my efficiency and effectivity.

www.pablocardone.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-garcia-cardone-841077165

Based in Leicester, England, United Kingdom

WORK EXPERIENCE

My Goal Physique

Jun 2020 – Present

Online E-Commerce & Digital Services Website

Position: Founder

- Overall website design & development
- SEO Optimisation Utilising a wide array of different tools and strategies as to boost and optimise search engine results, website popularity and traffic flow
- Content development Content research & writing of all website articles
- Product Selection Product research, opportunity identification and product line-up selection
- Supply Chain Management Effectively liaising with international suppliers and shipping services
- Marketing and promotion (Google & Facebook Ads) Market research & analysis, opportunity identification, advertisement design and management of social media channels
- Finance Carrying out all of the website's finance planning and marketing budgeting

De Montfort University Leicester, United Kingdom

Nov 2019 – Present

Position: Applicant Relationship Manager

- Working closely with the International Student Office to achieve set targets by providing expert and consultative customer service to potential international students
- Addressing potential international students concerns and ensuring resolution of issues in a timely manner through different communication channels
- Daily working, monitoring and updating of Excel spreadsheets
- Conducting extensive market research to identify new trends in student recruitment
- Collaborating with team members on strategies to increase student recruitment and engagement

WORK EXPERIENCE

De Montfort University Leicester, United Kingdom

Jul 2020 – Present

Position: UniBuddy

- Representing De Montfort University on the UniBuddy platform and building a rapport with enquirers.
- Offering support and advice to upcoming and current DMU student regarding a wide range of topics in relation to DMU and Leicester.
- Assisting enquirers in finding the right information and contact details for particular

www.pablocardone.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-garcia-cardone-841077165

Based in Leicester, England, United Kingdom

departments at DMU.

• Providing a real insight into DMU's University experience through chats and blogs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bright Network Online Internship

Jul 2020 - Jul 2020

Position: Bright Network Internship Experience UK - Business, Operations and Marketing

- Learned key industry insights from partnered firms that include Google, GSK, Enterprise, M&S and P&G.
- Took part in industry workshops and harnessed industry relevant skills.
- Developed and presented a practical work project based on real life business conditions.

Erskine Murray Insurance Brokers Leicester, United Kingdom

Apr 2019 – Jun 2019

Position: Schemes Administrator

Duties:

- Working alongside Schemes Manager and underwriters in the preparation of new business quotations
- Data validation and quality improvement
- Contacting clients to help improve credit control position
- Contacting clients requesting confirmation that insurer's risk improvements have been implemented
- Keeping a log of all activities for audit purposes
- Completion of ad hoc tasks as required by the Schemes Manager

Edu4u Jun 2018 – Nov 2018

Leicester, United Kingdom

Position: International Relationships Advisor

Duties:

- Liaising with students and academic institutions
- Supporting the development of the Edu4u website
- Working as part of a team analysing, evaluating and presenting new business and market opportunities
- Helping promote the company through direct marketing & events management
- Leading and designing a business expansion project focused on entering the Spanish market

www.pablocardone.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-garcia-cardone-841077165

Based in Leicester, England, United Kingdom

BSS

Aug 2018 - Sep 2018

Leicester, United Kingdom

Position: Office Administrator in Supplier Support for the National Admin Team

Duties:

- Creating customers back orders
- Assisting with goods received reconciliation
- Process invoices daily based on Citrix
- Liaise with Sales Teams and Suppliers where required to escalate Invoice/Payment queries for efficient resolution of disputes
- Precise matching to GRN's and purchase orders
- Supplier query resolution- by email and phone

Erskine Murray Insurance Brokers Leicester, United Kingdom

Jul 2018 – Aug 2018

Position: Data Processor

Duties:

- Assisting with schemes preparation and entering data into databases
- Verified accuracy of data before and after entry into system
- Stored, retrieved, and maintained data
- Utilised strong project and time management skills to ensure all projects were completed on time
- Added new material to file records and created new records
- Gained knowledge, and utilized the "Acturis" Insurance Software
- Entered numerical data into databases in a timely and accurate manner
- Inspected database errors and resolved discrepancies

Royal Voluntary Service Leicester, United Kingdom

July 2018 – December 2018

Position: Office Administrator

Duties:

- Creating, updating, and maintaining management information systems along with producing relevant reports
- Managing, organizing, and updating database applications with relevant volunteer/client/service/user/staff data

www.pablocardone.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-garcia-cardone-841077165

Based in Leicester, England, United Kingdom

• Communicating and providing information by relevant methods internally and externally to ensure all referrals/inquiries/complaints are dealt with effectively in accordance with organisation operating procedures

EDUCATION

De Montfort University, Leicester Risk Management MSc

Sept 2019 – June 2020

Grade: Predicted Distinction

Modules studied (1st Trimester & 2nd Trimester):

- Risk Management
- Project Management
- Business Continuity and Crisis Management
- Research Methodology
- Risk Management 2
- Assurance and Risk
- Strategic Financial and Decision-making
- Global Supply Chain Management
- Dissertation ("An ethical approach to the implementation of better crisis communications in relation to crisis management")

De Montfort University, Leicester Business & Management (Hons)

Sept 2016 – June 2019

Grade: First Class

Modules studied (1st, 2nd & 3rd year):

- Academic and Professional Practice
- English for Academic Purposes Advanced
- Financial Decision Making
- Global Business Issues
- Brand Management
- Contemporary Management
- Human Resource Management in the Workplace
- International Marketing
- Global Contemporary Business Issues
- Social Innovation and Entrepreneurship
- Service Operations Management
- Global Strategic Management
- Crisis & Business Continuity Management

www.pablocardone.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-garcia-cardone-841077165

Based in Leicester, England, United Kingdom

Compass International School of Doha, Qatar International Baccalaureate Certificate (26 points)

May 2014 - June 2016

- My goals for when I was doing the International Baccalaureate (IB) were to further improve myself in not only subject-related knowledge but also as an individual.
- During the period of my IB course, I learned key aspects that I believe can be directly transferred to a working environment. Such skills include: teamwork, team leadership, effective time management, increased sense of responsibility, creativity, and critical thinking.
- The three most important, major aspects that I am grateful to have learned and value during my IB were essay writing, preparing presentations and developing strong social skills. I consider these skills the most valuable as I was able to transfer and apply them in real life situations as well as in University.

Compass International School of Doha, Qatar IGCSE's

Mar 2012 – Feb 2014

6 IGCSE's including English & Maths

Additional Skills

- Enthusiastic Can easily find enjoyment in work and encouraging colleagues
- Outgoing Friendly, respectful, and approachable
- Flexible Capable of switching routines when needed
- Time Management Able to manage my time in a way that work never interferes with my studies or hobbies
- Determined Highly motivated to achieve my goals and act by my own initiative
- Cultural awareness Great understanding of diversity and equality
- Bi-Lingual Fluent in both English and Spanish

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Successfully developed and launched a profitable e-commerce business
- Predicted distinction for my current postgraduate degree in Risk Management
- Elected course representative for Risk Management MSc
- Achieved a 1st class degree for my Business and Management University undergraduate course
- Successfully completed my International Baccalaureate course with a score of 26 points

www.pablocardone.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-garcia-cardone-841077165 Based in Leicester, England, United Kingdom

Personal interests

- Travelling
- Reading
- Meeting with friends and family
- Fitness

REFERENCES

References are available on request.